<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on RUISI CAI</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on RUISI CAI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Ruisi Cai 蔡睿思
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 19:41:22 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Randomized Channel Shuffling, Minimal-Overhead Backdoor Attack Detection without Clean Datasets</title>
      <link>/projects/randomized_channel_shuffling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 19:41:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/randomized_channel_shuffling/</guid>
      <description>Deep neural networks (DNNs) typically require massive data to train on, which is a hurdle for numerous practical domains. Facing the data shortfall, one viable option is to acquire domain-specific training data from external uncensored sources, such as open webs or third-party data collectors. However, the quality of such acquired data is often not rigorously scrutinized, and one cannot easily rule out the risk of ``poisoned&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; examples being included in such unreliable datasets, resulting in unreliable trained models which pose potential risks to many high-stake applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust Weight Signatures Gaining Robustness as Easy as Patching Weights?</title>
      <link>/projects/robust_weight-signatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 19:41:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/robust_weight-signatures/</guid>
      <description>Given a robust model trained to be resilient to one or multiple types of distribution shifts (e.g., natural image corruptions), how is that &amp;ldquo;robustness&amp;rdquo; encoded in the model weights, and how easily can it be disentangled and/or &amp;ldquo;zero-shot&amp;rdquo; transferred to some other models? This paper empirically suggests a surprisingly simple answer: linearly - by straightforward model weight arithmetic! We start by drawing several key observations: (1)assuming that we train the same model architecture on both a clean dataset and its corrupted version, resultant weights mostly differ in shallow layers; (2)the weight difference after projection, which we call &amp;ldquo;Robust Weight Signature&amp;rdquo; (RWS), appears to be discriminative and indicative of different corruption types; (3)for the same corruption type, the RWSs obtained by one model architecture are highly consistent and transferable across different datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
