<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RUISI CAI</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on RUISI CAI</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Ruisi Cai 蔡睿思
</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 19:41:22 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 19:41:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>Education 2022-Present Ph.D in Electrical and Computer Engineering, the University of Texas at Austin
2018-2022 B.E. in Electronic Information Engineering, University of Science and Technology of China
Research Experience 2022.9 - present The University of Texas at Austin Graduate research assistant, advised by Prof. Atlas Wang. 2020.5 - 2022.5 University of Science and Technology of China Undergraduate research assistant, advised by Prof. Dong Liu. Awards Oct 2021 Suzhou Talent scholarship (top 5% at USTC) Nov 2020 Second Prize in Chinese Mathematical Competitions for University Students Oct 2020 Silver Prize for Outstanding Student Scholarship (top 10% at USTC) May 2020 First Prize (Team) at 2020 USTC Innovation Contest on Energy Saving &amp;amp; Emission Reduction Oct 2019 Silver Prize for Outstanding Student Scholarship (top 10% at USTC) Skills Deep Learning Frameworks: Pytorch, Tensorflow Programming Languages: C, Python, MATLAB, Verilog Applications: AutoCAD, Solidworks, Photoshop, Origin Professional Service Reviewer ICML 2023, ICASSP 2023 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Randomized Channel Shuffling, Minimal-Overhead Backdoor Attack Detection without Clean Datasets</title>
      <link>/projects/randomized_channel_shuffling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 19:41:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/randomized_channel_shuffling/</guid>
      <description>Deep neural networks (DNNs) typically require massive data to train on, which is a hurdle for numerous practical domains. Facing the data shortfall, one viable option is to acquire domain-specific training data from external uncensored sources, such as open webs or third-party data collectors. However, the quality of such acquired data is often not rigorously scrutinized, and one cannot easily rule out the risk of ``poisoned&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; examples being included in such unreliable datasets, resulting in unreliable trained models which pose potential risks to many high-stake applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust Weight Signatures Gaining Robustness as Easy as Patching Weights?</title>
      <link>/projects/robust_weight-signatures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 19:41:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/robust_weight-signatures/</guid>
      <description>Given a robust model trained to be resilient to one or multiple types of distribution shifts (e.g., natural image corruptions), how is that &amp;ldquo;robustness&amp;rdquo; encoded in the model weights, and how easily can it be disentangled and/or &amp;ldquo;zero-shot&amp;rdquo; transferred to some other models? This paper empirically suggests a surprisingly simple answer: linearly - by straightforward model weight arithmetic! We start by drawing several key observations: (1)assuming that we train the same model architecture on both a clean dataset and its corrupted version, resultant weights mostly differ in shallow layers; (2)the weight difference after projection, which we call &amp;ldquo;Robust Weight Signature&amp;rdquo; (RWS), appears to be discriminative and indicative of different corruption types; (3)for the same corruption type, the RWSs obtained by one model architecture are highly consistent and transferable across different datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1</title>
      <link>/docs/example-doc/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/example-doc/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is chapter 1 of example doc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1</title>
      <link>/docs/example-doc/nested-chapter/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/example-doc/nested-chapter/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is chapter 1 of nested chapter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2</title>
      <link>/docs/example-doc/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/example-doc/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is chapter 2 of example doc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2</title>
      <link>/docs/example-doc/nested-chapter/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/example-doc/nested-chapter/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is chapter 2 of nested chapter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
